trinidadexpress.com 2019-12-15

# Privacy Policy | Site | trinidadexpress.com

At One Caribbean we are committed to protecting the privacy, accuracy and reliability of any personal information you choose to provide and to safeguarding such information from loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction. This Privacy Policy applies to those websites that are part of One Caribbean.

Please read this Privacy Policy carefully. This Privacy Policy may change from time to time, so please check back often. If you have any questions or comments regarding this Privacy Policy, please contact us by sending an e-mail message to [webmaster@ccngroup.com](mailto:webmaster@ccngroup.com).

 **Collection of Personal Information**

You do not need to provide any information that identifies you ("personal information") to use a One Caribbean site or to obtain information from most of the features of a One Caribbean site. In general, you can visit our websites without telling us who you are or revealing any personal information.

However, if you want to use certain online services, you may be asked to provide some personal information, such as your name, mailing address or e-mail address. We also may ask you to choose a user name and password and provide that information when accessing certain online features. If you do not want to give us any personal information, you can always decide not to use the services. The choice is yours. We are only interested in offering you convenient online services that match your interests and needs.

Some examples of when we may request personal information include the following:

E-News. You can register to receive notifications from One Caribbean sites about issues of personal interest, such as local weather, traffic and sports information. In order to provide you with these e-mail notifications, we may ask you to provide certain personal information, such as your name and e-mail address.

Polls. Many One Caribbean sites offer polling areas, which provide users with an opportunity to vote on local and national issues of concern. When you choose to participate in a poll, we may ask you to provide your name and e-mail address. This information helps us ensure the accuracy of our polling data.

Surveys. One Caribbean sites also may allow users to complete surveys about products or services offered by One Caribbean or other companies. These surveys may ask for your name and e-mail address, and/or other information, such as your gender and income level. This information helps us understand our survey results.

Contests/Trivia. One Caribbean sites also afford users many opportunities to play contests or trivia games. When you enter into a contest, trivia game or any other promotional item, we may ask for your name, password information and address (physical and electronic) so that we can contact you if you win. Sometimes we may require you to provide additional information, such as your gender and income level. Of course, if you do not want to provide such information, you do not need to participate in the online activity.

Purchases. Some One Caribbean sites enable users to purchase products. When you purchase products, we may request your name, address, telephone number and credit card information. This information allows us to send you the items you ordered, to process payment information, and to respond to product and billing questions.

Chat/Message Boards. One Caribbean sites also may offer users the chance to participate in public forums, such as chat rooms, message boards and/or news groups. When you choose to participate in any of these forums, we may request your name, password information and address (physical and electronic). This information helps us respond to questions or concerns about use of these public areas.

Comments/Questions. You may send us comments or questions about your use of the One Caribbean site. You need not identify yourself to send a comment or question, but we may collect your e-mail address so that we can send you a response. If you choose to provide other personal information in your comment or question, we may keep it in our correspondence files.

The above list contains some of the instances when the One Caribbean website may collect your personal information. Please note that many of our websites may offer additional online features and services and may ask you to provide some personal information before permitting you to access those areas. This Privacy Policy governs the collection of any personal information you provide to a One Caribbean site.

 **Use and Disclosure of Personal Information**

The One Caribbean website uses your personal information for three general purposes. First, we use the information to provide you with the services you request and to respond to billing and/or other questions related to such service offerings. Second, we use the information to understand your use of our websites and to notify you about updates to one of our sites or to send you marketing materials or promotional offers that may be of interest. Third, we may use this information in aggregate form to help us evaluate and modify existing services and to help us develop additional services that are likely to be of interest to our users.

We may share your personal information with unaffiliated third parties in limited instances. For example, we may share your personal information with unaffiliated third parties as is necessary to process or collect payments, or service registered-user accounts. We also may hire third-party technology providers to host the One Caribbean websites and to store your personal information.

We may also share aggregate, non-personal information about website usage with unaffiliated third parties, including, but not limited to, government agencies, advertisers and the media (i.e., 50% of One Caribbean, Inc., website users are female, 50% of users have visited certain sections, etc.). This aggregate information does not contain any personal information about our users.

We may use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit the One Caribbean website. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visit to the One Caribbean website in order to provide advertisements about goods and services that may be of interest to you. In the course of serving advertisements to the One Caribbean website, our third-party advertisers may place or recognize a unique "cookie" on your browser. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by advertising companies, please send an e-mail to [webmaster@ccngroup.com](mailto:webmaster@ccngroup.com).

Finally, we may be required to disclose personal information by law or legal process, to protect and defend the rights or property of a One Caribbean site, or to protect the personal safety of users to one of our sites. We also reserve the right to contact appropriate authorities when activities that are illegal or violate our policies are taking place on the One Caribbean website.

Except under the limited circumstances described above, we will not disclose any of your personal information to unaffiliated third parties.

 **How We Protect Personal Information**

We take reasonable measures to protect the privacy, accuracy, and reliability of any information you choose to provide and to protect such information from loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction. Only authorized employees and partners are permitted to access personal information, and they only may do so for permitted business functions. Any employee or partner who violates our privacy access policies will be subject to disciplinary action and/or termination.

 **Accessing or Deleting Your Personal Information**

If you have submitted personal information through a One Caribbean website and you would like to access that information, please send an e-mail to One Caribbean at webmaster@ccngroup.com. We will use reasonable efforts to supply you with this information and to correct any factual inaccuracies that you identify. Upon your request, we also will remove your personal information from our databases.

 **Collection, Use and Disclosure of Non-Personal Information**

In some cases, a One Caribbean site may collect information about you that is not personally identifiable, as described below. Internet Protocol Addresses An Internet Protocol (IP) address is a number automatically assigned to your computer whenever you access the Internet. This number does not identify your name, e-mail address or other personal information. If you request pages from any One Caribbean website, that site's server will enter your IP address into a log.

To maintain user anonymity, One Caribbean does not associate IP addresses with records containing personal information. We also do not permit IP addresses to be associated and viewed with posts to chat rooms and bulletin boards. We store IP addresses for a period of time to help us to identify anyone who refuses to comply with our in-house rules or terms of service, and to identify visitors who threaten our service, site, customers or others. We also will use this information to measure site traffic for purposes of system administration and for our sponsors. This aggregate data also helps us to understand how people are using the website and helps us improve your online experience.

We allow third-party companies to serve ads and/or collect certain anonymous information when you visit our web site. These companies may use non-personally identifiable information (e.g., click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over) during your visits to this and other web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of interest to you. These companies typically use a cookie or third party web beacon to collect this information. To learn or more about this behavioral advertising practice or to opt-out of this type of advertising for some companies, you can visit [http://www.networkadvertising.org](http://www.networkadvertising.org/) and <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>

**Cookies**

One Caribbean sites also automatically gather certain non-personal information through the use of "cookies". "Cookies" are small text files that recognize repeat visitors, facilitate ongoing access to some sites, and allow sites to understand how and when pages are visited and by how many people. We use cookies primarily to make improvements and updates based on which areas are popular and which are not. We also use cookies to ensure the accuracy of our polling data.

Our advertisers may occasionally place cookies on your computer, which is standard in the Internet industry. Please note that One Caribbean does not control these cookies. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by advertising companies, please send an e-mail to webmaster@ccngroup.com.

 **Safeguarding Children’s Privacy**

One Caribbean sites will not knowingly collect personal information or any other identifying data from children under 13 years of age without first obtaining verifiable consent from a parent or legal guardian. Requests for parental consent will explain how we collect, use, and disclose children's personal information, and will include an opportunity for parents to prevent use of their children's information, as well as to prevent their children from participating in features which involve the collection of personal information. Should a child whom we know to be under 13 send personal information to a One Caribbean site without first obtaining parental consent, the site will immediately delete that information from its database.

We will not use, distribute or disclose any child's personal information to third parties without prior parental consent. If, at any time, a parent withdraws his or her consent to our use or maintenance of personal information collected from his or her child, we will promptly remove such information from our database. In addition, we will not require children under 13 years of age to disclose more personal information than is necessary in order to participate in any online feature or service.

 **External Links**

One Caribbean sites may provide links to various websites. When you click on one of these links, you will be transferred from a One Caribbean website and connected to the website of the organization or company that you selected. Even if an affiliation exists between One Caribbean and a third-party website, One Caribbean exercises no control over linked sites. Each of these linked sites maintains its own independent privacy and data collection policies and procedures. If you visit a website that is linked to a One Caribbean site, you should consult that site's Privacy Policy before providing those sites with any of your personal information.

 **Terms, Changes and Questions**

By using a One Caribbean website, you signify your agreement to the terms of our Privacy Policy. If you do not agree with these terms, please do not use or disclose any personal information through one of our sites.

If we decide to change this Privacy Policy, we will post those changes here so that you will always know what information we gather, how we might use that information, and whether we will disclose it to anyone.

If you have any questions or comments about this policy or our use of personal information, you may send an e-mail to [webmaster@ccngroup.com](mailto:webmaster@ccngroup.com) or send a letter to the following address:

35-37 Independence Square Port of Spain Trinidad W.I.

We will use reasonable efforts to promptly investigate any complaint you may have regarding our use of personal information.
